invitationhomes.com 2017-06-21

# Homes | Invitation Homes

**Privacy Policy**

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY.

By accessing or otherwise using this Website you agree to be bound contractually by this Privacy Policy.

Effective Date: August 7, 2013

1\. Privacy Policy. THR Property Management LP and/or its local affiliate (collectively, "THR") operate this Website. All references to "we", "us", “our” and similar terms shall refer to THR. We regard the privacy and security of user information as a critical component of the services that we offer to our users. The following information explains our information gathering and dissemination practices.

2\. Modification of Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, upon prior notice to you by email, and by thereafter posting amended terms on this Website. Your continued use after such notice, indicates your acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy. You should check this Privacy Policy periodically for modifications by referencing the Effective Date posted above.

3\. Additional "Click-Wrapped" Agreements. This Privacy Policy provides our general policies regarding the collection and use of private information and our use of email to contact you. We reserve the right to offer to you participation in such additional agreements in "click-wrapped" format (where you may indicate your agreement by clicking on a button or icon) that may provide specific exceptions to these general policies. If there is any inconsistency or conflict between this Privacy Policy and any such "click-wrapped" agreement, the "click-wrapped" agreement shall prevail.

4\. Registration Data. We reserve the right to require you to register to receive certain benefits or services and to provide certain registration data including your name, country, zip code or postal code (as appropriate) and email address ("Registration Data").

5a. Personally Identifiable Data. Personally identifiable information is any information that concerns you individually or can be used to identify or contact you (“Personally Identifiable Information”).  For example, the Registration Data includes Personally Identifiable Information as does any other information you submit that identifies you individually. We will not collect any Personally Identifiable Information from you unless you voluntarily submit such information to us. Therefore, if you do not want us to obtain any Personally Identifiable Information about you, do not voluntarily submit such information to us. You do not have to provide us with any Personally Identifiable Information to visit or browse our Website. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, you may not be able to visit or view all sections of our website or receive any of our services. If you become a registered user and make postings on the Website, we may collect information about your postings. This information may include, without limitation, areas of our Website on which you post, the content of your post, posts that responded to, and the individuals or entities with whom you communicate. You may also choose to communicate with us through email, via our website, via telephone, in writing, or though any other means. We collect all information in these communications, and because such information may be Personally Identifiable Information, we will only use such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

5b.       Automatic Collection of Non-Personally Identifiable Information. When you visit or browse our Website, or become a registered user of our Website, we may also collect information that by itself cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (like age, profession or gender) (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”). Non-Personally Identifiable Information may also include certain anonymous information about the type of browser you use, the server name and IP address through which you access the Internet (such as “aol.com” or “earthlink.net”), the date and time you access our website, the pages you access while on our website, and the Internet address of the Website, if any, from which you linked directly to our Website. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is used to help us or our third party vendors to understand the characteristics of people who visit our website and to improve and market our website in general. In the event that we link any Non-Personally Identifiable Information with Personally Identifiable Information, we will treat such information as Personally Identifiable Information and only use such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

5c. Information We Use. Among other things, we may use the Personally Identifiable Information collected through our website for such purposes as:

•           helping to establish and verify the identity of users;

•           opening, maintaining, administering and servicing users’ accounts or memberships;

•           processing postings and sending related communications;

•           providing services and support to users;

•           improving our Website, including tailoring it to users’ preferences;

•           responding to users’ questions, inquiries, comments and instructions;

•           maintaining the security and integrity of our systems; and

•           fulfilling user’s service orders. 

In general, except as otherwise provided, we use the Personally Identifiable Information collected on our website to help us or our third party vendors understand who uses our Website and how it is used, to personalize your experience, to assist you in using our Website and to improve our Website.

If you become a registered member of our Website, we may use your information to send you a welcoming email that may confirm your user name and password. If you decide to “opt-in” we may send you electronic newsletters, contact you about our services, related information and news items that may be of interest to you, and provide you with targeted feedback.  If you decide you no longer want to receive these communications from us, we will provide you with an option to “opt-out” and change your preferences. 

Except as otherwise provided, we also use the Non-Personally Identifiable Information collected automatically by our servers to help us administer and improve our Website.

 6\. Cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a web site if you do so. We reserve the right to use cookies to collect demographic and profile data for purposes of delivering content specific to your interests. Advertisers that display ads on our Website may also use cookies; however we do not have access to the information obtained from cookies issued from other sites.

7\. IP Addresses. IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as "traffic data" so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you. We will not use your IP address to attempt to identify your personal information.

8\. Referrers. A  Referrer is the information passed along by a web browser that references the Web URL you linked from, and is automatically collected by our web server as "traffic data". We reserve the right to use this information to identify broad demographic trends that may be used to provide information tailored to your interests or in connection with agreements that we may have with the referring web site. You will not be personally identified from this information.

9\. System Information. System information that we collect as part of "traffic data" includes time, the type of web browser being used, the operating system/platform, and CPU speed. This information is sent automatically by your web browser when you are connected to a web site. We reserve the right to use this information for purposes of identifying broad demographic trends and may be used to provide information appropriate for your computer system. You will not be personally identified from this information.

10\. Sharing of Information. We feel strongly that your personal data should only be seen by you, unless you choose to share it with others. We will never sell, rent, license or exchange personally identifiable data with a third party without your permission, except as otherwise provided. No personally identifiable data or information will be shared with advertisers or partners without your permission. Some of your information may be shared on an aggregate basis only, as a part of a larger set of statistics (for example, statistics that indicate the percentage of our members that are female, etc.), but that information will not be sufficient to permit the recipient to identify you. Notwithstanding the forgoing, we will only disclose personally identifiable data without your permission in the following limited circumstances: (i) if we are required to do so by law, or (ii) if we have the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to applicable laws or comply with legal process served on us, or to protect and defend our rights or property or the rights or property of a user of this Website, or as otherwise provided in this policy. We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information about you to our affiliates. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, "Affiliates" means any person or entity which directly or indirectly controls, is controlled by or is under common control with us, whether by ownership or otherwise. Any information relating to you that we provide to our Affiliates will be treated by those Affiliates in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We may provide to third parties information about you that does not allow you to be identified or contacted, including where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our Website. For instance, we may provide information to third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our Website, the demographic breakdown of the registered users of our Website, or the activities that visitors to our Website engage in while on our Website. The third parties to which we may provide this information may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising services (including Website tracking services), commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties. We may engage independent contractors, vendors and suppliers (collectively, "Outside Contractors") to provide specific services and products related to our Website and services, such as hosting and maintaining our message boards or chat rooms and developing applications for our Website and e-mail services or processing payments and data. These Outside Contractors may sometimes have limited access to information collected on our Website, including your Personally Identifiable Information, in the course of providing products or services to us or to you on our behalf. Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these Outside Contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for the Outside Contractors to perform their limited function for us. We also require that these Outside Contractors (i) protect the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, and (ii) not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with the products or services for which we contracted. 

11\. Other Web Sites, Links, And Advertisers. This Website contains links to other web sites. We reserve this right to have advertisers or other third parties on this Website who may also have links on this Website and may link to this Website. The privacy practices of advertisers or web sites linked to this Website are not covered by this privacy policy, and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites or third parties. Additionally, if you make a purchase from a store or merchant listed on or linked to this Website, any information that you give, such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to those merchants. These merchants have separate privacy and data collection practices, and we have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. You should be careful to review any privacy policies posted on any of these sites before signing up with and using them.

12\. Security. Information collected by this Website is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. Our employees or Outside Contractors are required by us to maintain and uphold your privacy and security and are aware of our privacy and security policies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, WE CANNOT ENSURE OR WARRANT THE SECURITY OF ANY INFORMATION YOU TRANSMIT TO US, AND YOU DO SO AT YOUR OWN RISK.

13\. No Liability for Acts of Third Parties. Although we will use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information (including credit card information), transmissions made by means of the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. We will have no liability for disclosure of information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. In addition, we will release specific information about you to comply with any valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute or court order. We will also release specific information in special cases, such as if there is an attempted breach of security or a physical threat to you or others.

Please note that if you give out personal identification information online -- that information can be collected and used by third parties. Although we strive to protect our users' privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of information you provide to us. You disclose such information at your own risk.

14\. Transfer of Your Information. As we continue to develop our activities, we might acquire or buy other entities or assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred assets. Also, in the event that all or substantially all of our assets or a controlling interest in us are acquired, both personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable user and customer information will be one of the transferred assets.

15. Minors. This Website is directed toward and designed for use by persons aged 18 or the age of majority in the jurisdiction in which you reside. We will not approve applications of, or establish or maintain accounts or memberships for, any child that we know to be under the age of 18. We do not solicit or knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from children under the age of 18. If we nevertheless discover that we have received Personally Identifiable Information from an individual who indicates that he or she is, or that we otherwise have reason to believe is, under the age of 18, we will promptly delete such information from our systems. Additionally, a child’s parent or legal guardian may request that the child’s information be corrected or promptly deleted from our files by contacting our Privacy Coordinator at the telephone number or address set out below.  

16\. Contact Us/Review Your Information/Opt-Out. If you have submitted personally identifiable information through this Website, or if someone else has submitted your personally identifiable information, and you would like to review, request changes or have that information deleted from our databases, please contact us via e-mail or send a letter to our Privacy Coordinator at the address indicated below. We will then use reasonable efforts to change or remove your personally identifiable information from our files, unless we are entitled or required to retain it pursuant to other agreements or by law. You may also contact us through either of the above methods to request or review the personally identifiable information that we have collected about you. We will use reasonable efforts to supply you with this information and correct any factual inaccuracies in this information. Our contact information is as follows:

Invitation Homes

1717 Main Street, Suite 2000

Dallas, TX  75201

Contact: Customer Service at [CustomerService@IHRent.com](mailto:CustomerService@IHRent.com)

_DMCA Notice_ __

If you have a copyright infringement claim regarding any materials posted on our website, you are directed to file a copyright infringement notice with us by sending a written communication that includes substantially the following information (please consult your attorney or review § 512(c)(3) of the United States Copyright Act to confirm the accuracy of these requirements):

(i) A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.

(ii) Identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed, or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site.

(iii) Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which is to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit us to locate the material.

(iv) Information reasonably sufficient to permit us to contact the complaining party, such as an address, telephone number, and, if available, an electronic mail address at which the complaining party may be contacted.

(v) A statement that the complaining party has a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law.

(vi) A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that the complaining party is authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed. 

Such written notice should be sent to our designated agent as follows:

DMCA Complaints

Invitation Homes

1717 Main Street, Suite 2000  
Dallas, TX 75201

Contact: Customer Service at [CustomerService@IHRent.com](mailto:CustomerService@IHRent.com)

Please also note that under § 512(f) of the United States Copyright Act, any person who knowingly makes a material misrepresentation that activities or materials are infringing a copyright may be subject to liability.

Counter-Notification.

If you elect to send us a counter notice, to be effective it must be a written communication provided to our designated agent that includes substantially the following (please consult your attorney or review § 512(g)(3) of the United States Copyright Act to confirm the accuracy of these requirements):

(A) A physical or electronic signature of the user.

(B) Identification of the material that has been removed or to which access has been disabled and the location at which the material appeared before it was removed or access to it was disabled.

(C) A statement under penalty of perjury that the user has a good faith belief that the material was removed or disabled as a result of mistake or misidentification of the material to be removed or disabled.

(D) The user’s name, address, and telephone number, and a statement that the user consents to the jurisdiction of Federal District Court for the judicial district in which the address is located, or if the user’s address is outside of the United States, for any judicial district in which we may be found, and that the user will accept service of process from the person who provided notification under subsection (c)(1)(C) or an agent of such person.

Such written notice should be sent to our designated agent as follows:

DMCA Complaints

Invitation Homes

1717 Main Street, Suite 2000  
Dallas, TX 75201

Contact: Customer Service at [CustomerService@IHRent.com](mailto:CustomerService@IHRent.com)

Please note that under Section 512(f) of the Copyright Act, any person who knowingly makes a material misrepresentation that material or activity was removed or disabled by mistake or misidentification may be subject to liability. 

Please also be advised that it is our policy to terminate users’ access to and use of this website in appropriate circumstances, where such users are repeat copyright infringers.

Updated: September, 2016

* * *

**_UNITED STATES RENTCafé PRIVACY POLICY_**

This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) of Yardi Systems, Inc. (collectively, with its subsidiaries and affiliates, “Yardi,” “we,” “us” or “our”) describes our privacy practices regarding information we collect from persons or entities in the United States (“you” or “your”) who access our RENTCafé websites or our related downloadable mobile applications that we may make available from time to time (collectively, the “Site”).

**PURPOSE.** The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you, including information gathered when you visit the Site, and information we may receive from third parties or affiliates in addition to that online information, how we may use that information, whether we disclose that information to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information. Yardi strives to help visitors of the Site protect their privacy while using our Site.

We collect information on behalf of property owners and managers who list or advertise properties on the Site and/or use services offered through the Site to communicate or transact with potential or actual renters (the “Property Managers”) and for our own use in connection with our operation of the Site. All information pertaining to the specific properties is passed along to that property’s Property Manager. This Privacy Policy governs our use of such information, but does not govern the use, storage and/or further collection of information that may occur at the property level, which use, storage and further collection will be governed by each property’s privacy policy. If made available to us, we will attempt to provide information indicating the location of the property’s privacy policy. If a privacy policy is not available for a property, we will provide appropriate contact information for the property and/or you should seek such information from the Property Manager.

THE SITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN AND YARDI DOES NOT KNOWINGLY SOLICIT OR COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION ON THE SITE FROM CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13. IF YARDI LEARNS THAT A CHILD UNDER THE AGE OF 13 HAS SUBMITTED PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO YARDI THROUGH THE SITE, IT WILL TAKE REASONABLE MEASURES TO DELETE SUCH INFORMATION FROM ITS RECORDS AND TO NOT USE SUCH INFORMATION FOR ANY PURPOSE (EXCEPT WHERE NECESSARY TO PROTECT THE SAFETY OF THE CHILD OR OTHERS, AS REQUIRED BY LAW, OR AS MAY OTHERWISE BE REQUIRED BY LAW).

**YOUR CONSENT AND POLICY CHANGES.** PLEASE READ THIS ENTIRE PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY. BY USING THE SITE, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT, WITHOUT QUALIFICATION, TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION, INCLUDING PERSONAL INFORMATION, AS DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU ARE NOT AUTHORIZED TO USE THE SITE.

Yardi may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Should the Privacy Policy be modified in any way, the new Privacy Policy will be posted to this webpage. As we may make changes from time to time without notifying you, we suggest that you periodically review the Privacy Policy. By using the Site after the effective date of any modification to the Privacy Policy, you expressly consent, without qualification, to the collection, use and disclosure of information, including Personally Identifiable Information (that you previously provided or later provide), as described in the new Privacy Policy.

**TYPES OF Information COLLECTED.** We collect two types of information: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you (“Personally Identifiable Information”). We also may collect information that by itself typically cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (e.g. age, profession or gender), user Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, domain names, internet service providers, referring/exit pages, date/time stamp, operating system, clickstream data, information about you such as how you use of the Site and your communication preferences, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Site (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”).

Personally Identifiable Information we collect may include your name, email addresses, postal addresses, ZIP codes, social security number, driver’s license number, prior addresses, monthly rent paid at prior residences, employers, job titles, income, telephone numbers, credit card information, bank account information and routing numbers, date of birth, gender, age, marital status, user name and password (if you choose to become a registered user of the Site or our products and services), emergency contact information, information about your pets, information about your vehicles including license plate numbers, and other information either desirable or necessary to provide quality services to our customers and visitors. We may also collect information about you such as your use of the Site and communication preferences.

You may choose not to provide your Personally Identifiable Information by not entering it on the Site; however you will not be able to use certain services and features if those services and features require Personally Identifiable Information in order to function.

**USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TECHNOLOGIES.** Like many other website operators, Yardi may use cookies to customize content specific to your interests and track your use of the Site. “Cookies” are text files that are placed on your computer and may be used to store your personal information. In addition to cookies, Yardi may use other now known or later developed technologies, to assist Yardi in observing the behavior of users visiting the Site. These technologies access individual user information but the information is used only to compile aggregated statistics about the Site’s usage.

This Site uses Google Analytics (and in the future may use other similar sites or services), a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), to better assist Yardi in understanding how the Site is used. Google Analytics will place cookies on your computer that will generate information that we select about your use of the Site, including your computer’s IP address. That information will be transmitted to and stored by Google. The information will be used for the purpose of evaluating consumer use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for Yardi’s use, and providing other services relating to Site activity and usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that by doing so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site. The use of cookies by Google Analytics is covered by Google’s privacy policy (<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>).

**How We Collect and Use Information.** We may collect information in several ways by your use of this Site, as well as from forms you submit to us, personal correspondence, such as emails or letters that you send to us, information you include in an application you complete on the Site, information you provide when scheduling a property visit through the Site, or any other activity through which you identify yourself to us. When you visit the Site, our servers may log your IP address, the URL of your request and other information that is provided in the HTTP header. We may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with personal information on this Site: for example, while many of the features of the Site are available without registering, you may be asked to create an account on the Site if you desire to access certain features. Further, in some instances, we may ask you to provide personal information in order to perform screening services for property managers or owners. Although you may decline to voluntarily provide Personally Identifiable Information when asked, some features, products and services will be unavailable to you as a result.

In addition, Property Managers and/or our third-party service providers may ask you voluntarily to provide personal information through our Site or on their websites and may share such personal information with us, as governed by their respective privacy policies. Our use of information received from a service provider will be dictated by the service provider's privacy policies and not this Privacy Policy.

If you choose to use the Refer a Friend email link to tell a friend about our site or a property listed on our site, we will ask for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Yardi stores this information for the purposes of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program only.

To the extent we are able to do so, we may link your Non-Personally Identifiable Information with your Personally Identifiable Information. We may also link information collected online with information we collect offline or collected online by third parties.

Yardi may use the information collected from you to provide services which you have requested from us: including, without limitation, sending your contact information to properties that you are interested in; sending your rental application to properties that you have selected; and enabling you to use the Resident Portal. We may also use your personal information to send you targeted messages, publications, news, and information about events, special offers, promotions and benefits. Yardi may use third-party service providers to send and distribute email and to perform other marketing and support functions. We may use information we collect from you to improve the content of this Site, to enhance users’ experiences when visiting this Site, to analyze trends, administer the Site, gather demographic information the Site’s users, track user movements and to customize the content and layout of this Site for each individual user.

**Email Management.** You may receive emails from Yardi and or RENTCafé for a variety of reasons - for example, if you took an action through the Services, you signed up for a regular report, you signed up for a saved search alert, or you added a property to your favorites list. We respect your desire to manage email correspondence. If you have an account with RENTCafé, you can select your preferences through your account settings. Also, you can manage your receipt of some types of communication by following the instructions included in the email we send you. Please note that, even if you unsubscribe from certain email correspondences, we may still need to email you with important transactional or administrative information. 

**Sharing of Information COLLECTED.** Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, we will not disclose any information we gather from you on our Site. We may share your personal information with the Property Managers that list apartments on the Site. We also may share your personal information with our third-party service providers (including payment processors and screening companies) or with other select third parties who offer goods or services we think may be of interest to you. From time to time, we may partner with other organizations or companies to provide co-sponsored or co-branded promotions, services or events and may share your personal information with our co-sponsor. We also may provide your personal information to service providers or contractors to perform functions on our behalf, such as, but not limited to, companies or individuals hired to: communicate news, deliver Yardi’s promotional materials via e-mail and direct mail, to develop, enhance, market or provide any of Yardi’s products, to process credit card payments and to assist Yardi with sending communications and performing other marketing and support functions. These third parties may use technologies to measure the effectiveness of ads and emails and use information about your visits to our Site so that we may provide you with a better experience on our Site. Yardi also may use third-party social media platforms, including third-party social media websites, to communicate with you.

We also may share with third parties, including, without limitation, our corporate partners, aggregated demographic and statistical information that is not personally identifiable (including, for example, the number of users who searched for certain types of housing, the daily number of unique visitors to the Site, how many users clicked on a particular advertisement and how many users were using a certain internet service provider).

Yardi also may disclose an individual’s personal information:

  * to a person who in the reasonable judgment of Yardi is seeking the information as an agent of the individual;
  * in situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire;
  * to a third party or parties, where disclosure is required or permitted by law, a judicial proceeding, a criminal investigation, a court order, or legal process;  if, in the reasonable judgment of Yardi, it is necessary to enforce compliance with our internal policies or the Terms of Use, to prevent illegal activity or suspected fraud, or to protect our Site, customers, or others; and
  * to any other entity that acquires all or a portion of our organization by merger, reorganization, operation of law, or a sale of some or all of Yardi’s assets.

Yardi may be required to use or disclose your information in connection with a legal action or other proceeding, including without limitation, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request.

Through the Site, Yardi may make available areas that allow for user interaction, including blogs, forums, bulletin board services, chat areas, or other message and communications features. Some of these forums may require registration. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**How We Store Your Information.** Yardi is committed to protecting the security of any personal information you provide to us. We maintain commercially reasonable safeguards to maintain the security and privacy of personal information that you provide to us. In spite of these protections, Yardi cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted over the Internet. After your information reaches Yardi, however, it is stored on servers (or in the case of information received from you in person, in writing or over the phone, in physical storage areas) protected by procedures and technology designed to block reasonably foreseeable intrusions by unauthorized third parties. We may store and process your personal information in the United States or Canada or any other country in which we or our agents maintain facilities. By using the Site, you consent to the transfer of your information among these facilities, including those located outside your home country.

**Third-Party Websites.** This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Yardi. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that are accessible through this Site, including but not limited to any third-party websites that process payments or perform screenings on behalf of Yardi, any property website, and ForRent.com. Please be aware that third-party websites that process payments or perform screenings for Yardi and websites for our advertisers, sponsors, affiliated entities and other third parties that are accessible through this Site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. Yardi is not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites and will not be responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit.

**RETENTION AND DESTRUCTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION.** In order to provide you with the products and services you request, answer questions you may have about the products and services provided, and for our own accountability to external regulatory bodies, we retain your information for a period deemed reasonable under the circumstances. Information stored in client and contact directories are more difficult to systematically destroy, so we remove such information from time to time when it appears we will no longer have a need to contact you, however we will promptly remove such information upon your written request. Paper files containing personal information are destroyed by shredding, and we destroy electronic information by deleting it. When we discard hardware that was used to store data, we ensure that the data is completely and permanently erased or that the hardware is physically destroyed.

**ACCESSING, REVIEWING AND CHANGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.** You can see, review and change most of your personal information by logging into your account on RENTCafé and editing your Account Profile or by contacting us at the addresses below. If your personal information changes or is inaccurate, you must change it promptly. If we disagree that certain information is incorrect, we will include a brief statement from you on the discrepancy and, if you want us to, we will forward your brief statement on your behalf to anyone who received the information from us.

In some instances, where requested by you and a Property Manager, we will use your personal information to conduct a screening process and/or produce a screening report or provide your information to a screening company in order to obtain a screening report for the Property Manager. The screening report may include credit information. Under the Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.), you may have the right to access, view and correct credit information relating to you held by a credit bureau by contacting the credit bureau.

There may be circumstances where your personal information is not accessible, reviewable or able to be modified by you through your RENTCafé account. With some exceptions, you have the right to see what personal information we hold about you. Often all you have to do is ask. We can help you identify what records we might have about you and we will also try to help you understand any information you do not understand (such as abbreviated data or technical language). We may need to confirm your identity before providing you with this access, and we reserve the right to charge a nominal fee for such requests. In some cases, we may require that your request to us for access be made in writing. If we cannot give you access, we will tell you within 30 days or as soon as reasonably practicable and provide you with a reason, as best we can, as to why we cannot give you access.

If we collected personal information on behalf of a third party we may have conveyed that information directly to the third party. If so, it may not exist as part of our own records and you will have to go to the third party to see the information.

**Contact Us.** If you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy or the use of information collected, you can contact us by email at: [privacy@rentcafe.com](mailto:privacy@rentcafe.com)

Copyright © 2013 Yardi Systems, Inc.

**_CANADIAN RENTCafé PRIVACY POLICY_**

This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) of Yardi Systems, Inc. (collectively, with its subsidiaries and affiliates, “Yardi,” “we,” “us” or “our”) describes our privacy practices regarding information we collect from persons or entities in Canada (“you” or “your”) who access our RENTCafé websites or our related downloadable mobile applications that we may make available from time to time (collectively, the “Site”).

**PURPOSE.** The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you, including information gathered when you visit the Site, and information we may receive from third parties or affiliates in addition to that online information, how we may use that information, whether we disclose that information to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information. Yardi strives to help visitors of the Site protect their privacy while using our Site.

We collect information on behalf of property owners and managers who list or advertise properties on the Site and/or use services offered through the Site to communicate or transact with potential or actual renters (the “Property Managers”) and for our own use in connection with our operation of the Site. All information pertaining to the specific properties is passed along to that property’s Property Manager. This Privacy Policy governs our use of such information, but does not govern the use, storage and/or further collection of information that may occur at the property level, which use, storage and further collection will be governed by each property’s privacy policy. If made available to us, we will attempt to provide information indicating the location of the property’s privacy policy. If a privacy policy is not available for a property, we will provide appropriate contact information for the property and/or you should seek such information from the Property Manager.

THE SITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN AND YARDI DOES NOT KNOWINGLY SOLICIT OR COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION ON THE SITE FROM CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13. IF YARDI LEARNS THAT A CHILD UNDER THE AGE OF 13 HAS SUBMITTED PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO YARDI THROUGH THE SITE, IT WILL TAKE REASONABLE MEASURES TO DELETE SUCH INFORMATION FROM ITS RECORDS AND TO NOT USE SUCH INFORMATION FOR ANY PURPOSE (EXCEPT WHERE NECESSARY TO PROTECT THE SAFETY OF THE CHILD OR OTHERS, AS REQUIRED BY LAW, OR AS MAY OTHERWISE BE REQUIRED BY LAW).

**YOUR CONSENT AND POLICY CHANGES.** Please read this entire Privacy Policy carefully. By using the Site, you expressly consent, without qualification, to the collection, use and disclosure of information, including personal information, as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use the Site.

Yardi may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Should the Privacy Policy be modified in any way, the new Privacy Policy will be posted to this webpage. As we may make changes from time to time without notifying you, we suggest that you periodically review the Privacy Policy. By using the Site after the effective date of any modification to the Privacy Policy, you expressly consent, without qualification, to the collection, use and disclosure of information, including Personally Identifiable Information (that you previously provided or later provide), as described in the new Privacy Policy.

**TYPES OF Information COLLECTED.** We collect two types of information: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you (“Personally Identifiable Information”). We also may collect information that by itself typically cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (e.g. age, profession or gender), user Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, domain names, internet service providers, referring/exit pages, date/time stamp, operating system, clickstream data, information about you such as how you use of the Site and your communication preferences, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Site (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”).

Personally Identifiable Information we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, email addresses, postal addresses, postal codes, social insurance number, driver’s license number, prior addresses, monthly rent paid at prior residences, employers, job titles, income, telephone numbers, credit card information, bank account information and routing numbers, date of birth, gender, age, marital status, user name and password (if you choose to become a registered user of the Site or our products and services), emergency contact information, information about your pets, information about your vehicles including license plate numbers, and other information either desirable or necessary to provide quality services to our customers and visitors. We may also collect information about you such as your use of the Site and communication preferences.

You may choose not to provide your Personally Identifiable Information by not entering it on the Site; however you will not be able to use certain services and features if those services and features require Personally Identifiable Information in order to function.

**USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TECHNOLOGIES.** Like many other website operators, Yardi may use cookies to customize content specific to your interests and track your use of the Site. “Cookies” are text files that are placed on your computer and may be used to store your personal information. In addition to cookies, Yardi may use other now known or later developed technologies, to assist Yardi in observing the behavior of users visiting the Site. These technologies access individual user information but the information is used only to compile aggregated statistics about the Site’s usage.

This Site uses Google Analytics (and in the future may use other similar sites or services), a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), to better assist Yardi in understanding how the Site is used. Google Analytics will place cookies on your computer that will generate information that we select about your use of the Site, including your computer’s IP address. That information will be transmitted to and stored by Google. The information will be used for the purpose of evaluating consumer use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for Yardi’s use, and providing other services relating to Site activity and usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that by doing so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site. The use of cookies by Google Analytics is covered by Google’s privacy policy (<http://www.google.ca/policies/privacy/>).

**How We Collect and Use Information.** We may collect information in several ways by your use of this Site, as well as from forms you submit to us, personal correspondence, such as emails or letters that you send to us, information you include in an application you complete on the Site, information you provide when scheduling a property visit through the Site, or any other activity through which you identify yourself to us. When you visit the Site, our servers may log your IP address, the URL of your request and other information that is provided in the HTTP header. We may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with personal information on this Site: for example, while many of the features of the Site are available without registering, you may be asked to create an account on the Site if you desire to access certain features. Further, in some instances, we may ask you to provide personal information in order to perform screening services for property managers or owners. Although you may decline to voluntarily provide Personally Identifiable Information when asked, some features, products and services will be unavailable to you as a result.

In addition, Property Managers and/or our third-party service providers may ask you voluntarily to provide personal information through our Site or on their websites and may share such personal information with us, as governed by their respective privacy policies. Our use of information received from a service provider will be dictated by the service provider's privacy policies and not this Privacy Policy.

If you choose to use the Refer a Friend email link to tell a friend about our site or a property listed on our site, we will ask for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Yardi stores this information for the purposes of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program only.

To the extent we are able to do so, we may link your Non-Personally Identifiable Information with your Personally Identifiable Information. We may also link information collected online with information we collect offline or collected online by third parties.

Yardi may use the information collected from you to provide services which you have requested from us: including, without limitation, sending your contact information to properties that you are interested in; sending your rental application to properties that you have selected; and enabling you to use the Resident Portal. We may also use your personal information to send you targeted messages, publications, news, and information about events, special offers, promotions and benefits. Yardi may use third-party service providers to send and distribute email and to perform other marketing and support functions. We may use information we collect from you to improve the content of this Site, to enhance users’ experiences when visiting this Site, to analyze trends, administer the Site, gather demographic information the Site’s users, track user movements and to customize the content and layout of this Site for each individual user.

**Email Management.** You may receive emails from Yardi and or RENTCafé for a variety of reasons - for example, if you took an action through the Services, you signed up for a regular report, you signed up for a saved search alert, or you added a property to your favorites list. We respect your desire to manage email correspondence. If you have an account with RENTCafé, you can select your preferences through your account settings. Also, you can manage your receipt of some types of communication by following the instructions included in the email we send you. Please note that, even if you unsubscribe from certain email correspondences, we may still need to email you with important transactional or administrative information.

**SHARING OF INFORMATION COLLECTED.** Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, we will not disclose any information we gather from you on our Site. We may share your personal information with the Property Managers that list apartments on the Site. We also may share your personal information with our third-party service providers (including payment processors and screening companies) or with other select third parties who offer goods or services we think may be of interest to you. From time to time, we may partner with other organizations or companies to provide co-sponsored or co-branded promotions, services or events and may share your personal information with our co-sponsor. We also may provide your personal information to service providers or contractors to perform functions on our behalf, such as, but not limited to, companies or individuals hired to: communicate news, deliver Yardi’s promotional materials via e-mail and direct mail, to develop, enhance, market or provide any of Yardi’s products, to process credit card payments and to assist Yardi with sending communications and performing other marketing and support functions. These third parties may use technologies to measure the effectiveness of ads and emails and use information about your visits to our Site so that we may provide you with a better experience on our Site. Yardi also may use third-party social media platforms, including third-party social media websites, to communicate with you.

We also may share with third parties, including, without limitation, our corporate partners, aggregated demographic and statistical information that is not personally identifiable (including, for example, the number of users who searched for certain types of housing, the daily number of unique visitors to the Site, how many users clicked on a particular advertisement and how many users were using a certain internet service provider).

Yardi also may disclose an individual’s personal information:

  * to a person who in the reasonable judgment of Yardi is seeking the information as an agent of the individual;
  * in situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire;
  * to a third party or parties, where disclosure is required or permitted by law, a judicial proceeding, a criminal investigation, a court order, or legal process;
  * if, in the reasonable judgment of Yardi, it is necessary to enforce compliance with our internal policies or the Terms of Use, to prevent illegal activity or suspected fraud, or to protect our Site, customers, or others; and
  * to any other entity that acquires all or a portion of our organization by merger, reorganization, operation of law, or a sale of some or all of Yardi’s assets.

Yardi may be required to use or disclose your information in connection with a legal action or other proceeding, including without limitation, in response to a court order or a summons. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request.

Through the Site, Yardi may make available areas that allow for user interaction, including blogs, forums, bulletin board services, chat areas, or other message and communications features. Some of these forums may require registration. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**HOW WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION.** Yardi is committed to protecting the security of any personal information you provide to us. We maintain commercially reasonable safeguards to maintain the security and privacy of personal information that you provide to us. In spite of these protections, Yardi cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted over the Internet. After your information reaches Yardi, however, it is stored on servers (or in the case of information received from you in person, in writing or over the phone, in physical storage areas) protected by procedures and technology designed to block reasonably foreseeable intrusions by unauthorized third parties. We may store and process your personal information in the United States or Canada or any other country in which we or our agents maintain facilities. By using the Site, you consent to the transfer of your information among these facilities, including those located outside your home country.

**THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES.** This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Yardi. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that are accessible through this Site, including but not limited to any third-party websites that process payments or perform screenings on behalf of Yardi, any property website, and ForRent.com. Please be aware that third-party websites that process payments or perform screenings for Yardi and websites for our advertisers, sponsors, affiliated entities and other third parties that are accessible through this Site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. Yardi is not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites and will not be responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit.

**RETENTION AND DESTRUCTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION.** In order to provide you with the products and services you request, answer questions you may have about the products and services provided, and for our own accountability to external regulatory bodies, we retain your information for a period deemed reasonable under the circumstances. Information stored in client and contact directories are more difficult to systematically destroy, so we remove such information from time to time when it appears we will no longer have a need to contact you, however we will promptly remove such information upon your written request. Paper files containing personal information are destroyed by shredding, and we destroy electronic information by deleting it. When we discard hardware that was used to store data, we ensure that the data is completely and permanently erased or that the hardware is physically destroyed.

**ACCESSING, REVIEWING AND CHANGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.** You can see, review and change most of your personal information by logging into your account on RENTCafé and editing your Account Profile or by contacting us at the addresses below. If your personal information changes or is inaccurate, you must change it promptly. If we disagree that certain information is incorrect, we will include a brief statement from you on the discrepancy and, if you want us to, we will forward your brief statement on your behalf to anyone who received the information from us.

In some instances, where requested by you and a Property Manager, we will use your personal information to conduct a screening process and/or produce a screening report or provide your information to a screening company in order to obtain a screening report for the Property Manager. The screening report may include credit information. Under provincial legislation, you may have the right to access, view and correct credit information relating to you that is held by a credit report agency by contacting the credit report agency directly.

There may be circumstances where your personal information is not accessible, reviewable or able to be modified by you through your RENTCafé account. With some exceptions, you have the right to see what personal information we hold about you. Often all you have to do is ask. We can help you identify what records we might have about you and we will also try to help you understand any information you do not understand (such as abbreviated data or technical language). We may need to confirm your identity before providing you with this access, and we reserve the right to charge a nominal fee for such requests. In some cases, we may require that your request to us for access be made in writing. If we cannot give you access, we will tell you within 30 days or as soon as reasonably practicable and provide you with a reason, as best we can, as to why we cannot give you access.

If we collected personal information on behalf of a third party we may have conveyed that information directly to the third party. If so, it may not exist as part of our own records and you will have to go to the third party to see the information.

**CONTACT US.** If you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy or the use of information collected, you can contact our Information Officer by email at the following address: [privacy@rentcafe.com](mailto:privacy@rentcafe.com)

He or she will attempt to answer any questions or concerns you might have. If you wish to make a formal complaint about our privacy practices, you may make it in writing to our Information Officer. We will acknowledge receipt of your complaint, ensure that it is investigated promptly and that you are provided with a formal decision and reasons in writing.

This policy is made under the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act. It is a complex Act and provides some additional exceptions to the privacy principles that are too detailed to set out here. There are some rare exceptions to the commitments set out above.

For more general inquiries, the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Canada oversees the administration of the privacy legislation in the private sector. The Commissioner also acts as a kind of ombudsman for privacy disputes. The Information and Privacy Commissioner can be reached at:

  * Address: 112 Kent Street
  * Ottawa, ON K1A 1H3   
 
  * Phone: (613) 995-8210
  * Toll-free: (800) 282-1376
  * Facsimile: (613) 947-6850
  * TTY: (613) 992-9190
  * Website: [www.priv.gc.ca/en/](http://www.priv.gc.ca/en/)

Copyright © 2013 Yardi Systems, Inc.

Updated January 10, 2017
